<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Right directions for your academic goals</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Right directions for your academic goals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for PR instead of Study Permit in Canada</title>
      <link>/immigration/prinsteadpermit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/immigration/prinsteadpermit/</guid>
      <description>Canada is accepting more than ever!
&amp;ldquo;This is even for my friends already studying in Europe, East Asia, Australia, and United States&amp;rdquo;
After securing admission, or even before that, apply for Canadian PR instead of Study Permit if you&amp;rsquo;re under 31.
 Advantages:    You just have to secure admission in any university and then you can come without visa.
  Your tuition fees will be half as compared to study visa holder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters admission process in North America i.e. (US/Canada)</title>
      <link>/masters/stepstomasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/stepstomasters/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide towards your Masters Admission
Step 1: First and foremost, you have to give an IELTS/TOEFL exam which is required by almost every university. I say almost because some university exempt it for specific universities in Pakistan. After that, you have to give GRE, in case its required by where you&amp;rsquo;re applying. In Canada, only some universities require GRE, but in US its the opposite.
Step 2: You can either apply directly at university&amp;rsquo;s website or else you can contact a professor first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Motivation</title>
      <link>/facts/randommotivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/randommotivation/</guid>
      <description>Never settle down for less proficiency. Always push for a change. Push the limits of your comfort. Try to be better everyday. Strive for more skills, more power, more passion. Never be contempt with your skills and expertise.
A person who is stuck in a loop - takes a lunch box everyday to his workplace, comes back and be comfortable have zero effects on society. Become skillful and active enough to teach your children, brilliant enough to change the nation, wise enough to absorb the positivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are the Best Consultant for Yourself</title>
      <link>/facts/youarethebestconsultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/youarethebestconsultant/</guid>
      <description>Anyone can start a consultancy business today. But you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t contact a consultant. The reason is that if you are not willing to put effort into your career, why would they? If you need something desperately, for them it would just be a normal client application.
Just few months ago I was super busy and had to go to a consultant for family visa purpose. Given that I had collected all the documents, he just had to submit them at the right place and that was pretty much it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Over Procrastination</title>
      <link>/facts/getoverprocastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/getoverprocastination/</guid>
      <description>Good news for lazy people to avoid scams and agent fees.
Tremendous amount of people out there have zero motivation to put an effort yet they need a scholarship. The good news is that now there is a solution to this. Now you can get fully funded masters in Canada, Germany and US within 2 months for just 3 Lac Pakistani rupees (all visa and tickets inclusive).
The key point here is that you need to pay these 3 lac rupees to none other than yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Confuse the Professor</title>
      <link>/phd/issuesinemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/issuesinemail/</guid>
      <description>I feel like a lot of people misunderstood my previous post about searching for a Ph.D. scholarship in Canada.
The purpose of contacting a supervisor is to ask them to supervise your Ph.D. thesis. When someone asks a professor for a Ph.D admission instead of supervision it not just confuses the professor but also their response is generic i.e. Apply directly to the university.
If you asked a professor for admission and they advised you to apply directly to the department that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean in any sense that the professor is willing to support your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write an Email to a Professor? - Masters</title>
      <link>/masters/writingemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/writingemail/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people ping professors but never hear back.
First I will mention some important steps and then the structure of a perfect email that you can write to a professor.
Step.no.1: First of all, read the requirements of admission at the department&amp;rsquo;s website. Remember that unlike Pakistan, each department of a university has their own requirements.
If the requirements are clear then proceed to Step.no.2
Step.no.2: Go to professors personal website and search for the section of future students, prospective student or any such kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write an Email to a Professor? - PhD</title>
      <link>/phd/writingemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/writingemail/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people ping professors but never hear back.
First I will mention some important steps and then the structure of a perfect email that you can write to a professor.
Step.no.1: First of all, read the requirements of admission at the department&amp;rsquo;s website. Remember that unlike Pakistan, each department of a university has their own requirements.
If the requirements are clear then proceed to Step.no.2
Step.no.2: Go to professors personal website and search for the section of future students, prospective student or any such kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Computer Science Professor Have Become Super Easy</title>
      <link>/news/getoverprocastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/getoverprocastination/</guid>
      <description>Finding Computer Science professor became way easier now :)
Finally, we have a Computer Science specific ranking chart. A new way to rank computer science research teams around the world based on the number of publications they have in the top computing science journals. www[dot]csrankings[dot]org
Here is a way how you can use it to find and approach the best researchers in your area:- https://youtu.be/hOSl3xPmHiQ
Like this post or have questions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Powerful Things that a BS Masters and PhD Should Know</title>
      <link>/facts/6powerfulthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/6powerfulthings/</guid>
      <description>6 powerful things for BS MS and Ph.D students in Pakistan that we are not doing and we should do!
 Apply for International Summer Internships  Most of the top universities and research institutes in Europe and North america offer summer internships to undergraduate and masters students. Mostly these internships completely cover you expenses. During this internship, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to complete a research project under the supervision of a professor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are all Masters PhD Programs Funded in North America?</title>
      <link>/facts/fundingvsscholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/fundingvsscholarship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Funding situation for Masters Ph.D in North America&amp;rdquo;
Lots of people get confused about the funding and scholarship situation in North America generally or Canada to be specific.
The concept here is that every graduate student pursuing Masters and Doctoral degree is funded one way or another.
Some students are on funding offered by local department while some are at scholarships. There are few who don&amp;rsquo;t have either so the universities help them out find some part-time work so that they become able to support themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Paying for IELTS Preparation</title>
      <link>/facts/edxielts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/edxielts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;STOP PAYING FOR IELTS PREPARATION AND LEARN FROM IELTS OWN STAFF&amp;rdquo;
Its completely out of my understanding why people spend money to prepare for IELTS.
I see a lot of people confused and worried about where should they prepare for IELTS test.
Some take classes on-campus while some join skype sessions and pay large sum of cash for these services.
I just want everyone to know that there is a free self-paced online course available on the internet which is designed by the academics of University of Queensland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded PhD admission process in North America i.e. (US/Canada)</title>
      <link>/phd/stepstophd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/stepstophd/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide towards your PhD Admission in Canada
I have prepared this guide for those who are interested to pursue a fully-funded Ph.D in Canada after their Masters.
It&amp;rsquo;s a six step process:-
  Select universities
  Find the right faculty
  Contact professor
  Appear for interview
  Apply for university
  Apply for study permit
  Select Universities: You are supposed to select 10 universities to narrow down your scope and attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Services</title>
      <link>/services/myservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/myservices/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: Ask me as many questions as you want in the comment section at the bottom of this page
I offer the following services:
General Services
 S101. CV Critical Review and Editing S102. Building CV/Resume from scratch S103. SOP Critical Review and Editing S104. IELTS Speaking Preparation for Band &amp;gt; 7  Academic Services
 S201. Research Proposal Critical Review S202. Professor&amp;rsquo;s Email Review S203. Shortlisting 10 Universities according to your profile for Canada S204.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>