<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowledge about Masters Admissions on Right directions for your academic goals</title>
    <link>/masters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowledge about Masters Admissions on Right directions for your academic goals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/masters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters admission process in North America i.e. (US/Canada)</title>
      <link>/masters/stepstomasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/stepstomasters/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide towards your Masters Admission
Step 1: First and foremost, you have to give an IELTS/TOEFL exam which is required by almost every university. I say almost because some university exempt it for specific universities in Pakistan. After that, you have to give GRE, in case its required by where you&amp;rsquo;re applying. In Canada, only some universities require GRE, but in US its the opposite.
Step 2: You can either apply directly at university&amp;rsquo;s website or else you can contact a professor first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write an Email to a Professor? - Masters</title>
      <link>/masters/writingemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/writingemail/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people ping professors but never hear back.
First I will mention some important steps and then the structure of a perfect email that you can write to a professor.
Step.no.1: First of all, read the requirements of admission at the department&amp;rsquo;s website. Remember that unlike Pakistan, each department of a university has their own requirements.
If the requirements are clear then proceed to Step.no.2
Step.no.2: Go to professors personal website and search for the section of future students, prospective student or any such kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>