<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on Right directions for your academic goals</title>
    <link>/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on Right directions for your academic goals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for PR instead of Study Permit in Canada</title>
      <link>/immigration/prinsteadpermit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/immigration/prinsteadpermit/</guid>
      <description>Canada is accepting more than ever!
&amp;ldquo;This is even for my friends already studying in Europe, East Asia, Australia, and United States&amp;rdquo;
After securing admission, or even before that, apply for Canadian PR instead of Study Permit if you&amp;rsquo;re under 31.
 Advantages:   You just have to secure admission in any university and then you can come without visa.
 Your tuition fees will be half as compared to study visa holder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters admission process in North America i.e. (US/Canada)</title>
      <link>/masters/stepstomasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/stepstomasters/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide towards your Masters Admission
Step 1: First and foremost, you have to give an IELTS/TOEFL exam which is required by almost every university. I say almost because some university exempt it for specific universities in Pakistan. After that, you have to give GRE, in case its required by where you&amp;rsquo;re applying. In Canada, only some universities require GRE, but in US its the opposite.
Step 2: You can either apply directly at university&amp;rsquo;s website or else you can contact a professor first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Confuse the Professor</title>
      <link>/phd/issuesinemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/issuesinemail/</guid>
      <description>I feel like a lot of people misunderstood my previous post about searching for a Ph.D. scholarship in Canada.
The purpose of contacting a supervisor is to ask them to supervise your Ph.D. thesis. When someone asks a professor for a Ph.D admission instead of supervision it not just confuses the professor but also their response is generic i.e. Apply directly to the university.
If you asked a professor for admission and they advised you to apply directly to the department that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean in any sense that the professor is willing to support your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write an Email to a Professor? - Masters</title>
      <link>/masters/writingemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/writingemail/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people ping professors but never hear back.
First I will mention some important steps and then the structure of a perfect email that you can write to a professor.
Step.no.1: First of all, read the requirements of admission at the department&amp;rsquo;s website. Remember that unlike Pakistan, each department of a university has their own requirements.
If the requirements are clear then proceed to Step.no.2
Step.no.2: Go to professors personal website and search for the section of future students, prospective student or any such kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write an Email to a Professor? - PhD</title>
      <link>/phd/writingemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/writingemail/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people ping professors but never hear back.
First I will mention some important steps and then the structure of a perfect email that you can write to a professor.
Step.no.1: First of all, read the requirements of admission at the department&amp;rsquo;s website. Remember that unlike Pakistan, each department of a university has their own requirements.
If the requirements are clear then proceed to Step.no.2
Step.no.2: Go to professors personal website and search for the section of future students, prospective student or any such kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded PhD admission process in North America i.e. (US/Canada)</title>
      <link>/phd/stepstophd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/stepstophd/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide towards your PhD Admission
I have prepared this guide for those who are interested to pursue a fully-funded Ph.D in Canada after their Masters.
It&amp;rsquo;s a six step process:- 1. Select universities 2. Find the right faculty 3. Contact professor 4. Appear for interview 5. Apply for university 6. Apply for study permit
 Select Universities: You are supposed to select 10 universities to narrow down your scope and attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAUTION: This section contains &#34;Super Biased News&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Process Information</title>
      <link>/immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/immigration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge about Masters Admissions</title>
      <link>/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/masters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge about PhD Admissions</title>
      <link>/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Share Your Skill</title>
      <link>/shareskill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shareskill/</guid>
      <description>This project is to teach technical skills to Madrassah students. Coming soon insha&amp;rsquo;Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>