<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funding on Right directions for your academic goals</title>
    <link>/tags/funding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funding on Right directions for your academic goals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/funding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Motivation</title>
      <link>/facts/randommotivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/randommotivation/</guid>
      <description>Never settle down for less proficiency. Always push for a change. Push the limits of your comfort. Try to be better everyday. Strive for more skills, more power, more passion. Never be contempt with your skills and expertise.
A person who is stuck in a loop - takes a lunch box everyday to his workplace, comes back and be comfortable have zero effects on society. Become skillful and active enough to teach your children, brilliant enough to change the nation, wise enough to absorb the positivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are the Best Consultant for Yourself</title>
      <link>/facts/youarethebestconsultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/youarethebestconsultant/</guid>
      <description>Anyone can start a consultancy business today. But you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t contact a consultant. The reason is that if you are not willing to put effort into your career, why would they? If you need something desperately, for them it would just be a normal client application.
Just few months ago I was super busy and had to go to a consultant for family visa purpose. Given that I had collected all the documents, he just had to submit them at the right place and that was pretty much it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Over Procrastination</title>
      <link>/facts/getoverprocastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/getoverprocastination/</guid>
      <description>Good news for lazy people to avoid scams and agent fees.
Tremendous amount of people out there have zero motivation to put an effort yet they need a scholarship. The good news is that now there is a solution to this. Now you can get fully funded masters in Canada, Germany and US within 2 months for just 3 Lac Pakistani rupees (all visa and tickets inclusive).
The key point here is that you need to pay these 3 lac rupees to none other than yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Powerful Things that a BS Masters and PhD Should Know</title>
      <link>/facts/6powerfulthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/6powerfulthings/</guid>
      <description>6 powerful things for BS MS and Ph.D students in Pakistan that we are not doing and we should do!
 Apply for International Summer Internships  Most of the top universities and research institutes in Europe and North america offer summer internships to undergraduate and masters students. Mostly these internships completely cover you expenses. During this internship, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to complete a research project under the supervision of a professor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are all Masters PhD Programs Funded in North America?</title>
      <link>/facts/fundingvsscholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/fundingvsscholarship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Funding situation for Masters Ph.D in North America&amp;rdquo;
Lots of people get confused about the funding and scholarship situation in North America generally or Canada to be specific.
The concept here is that every graduate student pursuing Masters and Doctoral degree is funded one way or another.
Some students are on funding offered by local department while some are at scholarships. There are few who don&amp;rsquo;t have either so the universities help them out find some part-time work so that they become able to support themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>